Hello friends, whenever we go to a bank, for
cash deposit or cash
withdrawal, we always have to
fill a form first. Only after that we can
complete our transaction. Be it any
thing for which we have to apply or
make some changes, you have to
fill a form everywhere. Similarly, to claim insurance,
you will first have to
fill a claim form. If you do
not know how to do it, then you will have to take someone's help.
But if you know how to do it, then you
can help three, four, five or unlimited people. So, in today's video, we will
learn how to fill an
insurance claim form for an insurance policy.
Hello friends, my name is Harvinder
Singh and I welcome you
to the YouTube channel of DSC Solutions, where
understanding insurance is very easy. You will get answers to
all your questions related to insurance here. Do
subscribe to the channel if
you have not subscribed yet. We have to
reach our message to where
it is most needed. So friends, what
you are seeing on the screen right now is the
personal accident claim form of ICICI Lombard,
as shown on the room.  It is written that the
personal accidental claim form of every company
or for any other is the same, the
same information is asked in it,
its format may be different, the
design may be different, but the
information that we have to fill in it
remains the same, so you will also get the idea
from the sentence, as if we click on it and
see, at the top here it
is written, The Adventures of Which Form is not to be
taken Admission of Liability, this means
that if we send you this claim form, it does
not mean that we have
approved your claim, it means that we have accepted the
liability,
this is only for collecting information, it does
not confirm the use of any claim, now the topper
box that you see here is the first one in which there
is the cover note or policy number,
you will see this polythene number in your policy,
against this we have to
click here,
write everything in capital letters
and clearly see here, nothing like this  It should
not be visible clearly, the setting number has the
period of insurance, from
when was the policy, suppose last year it was 10th
August 2002 to 9th August 2012,
then here we will write it in this format
EMYY i.e.
10060 2021 in between, right of justice - let it be correct,
after that the new innings which is about to end is
9th August
08 09 2012 2022 DM and in this format,
both have to be written from beginning to end, the
date of accident on which day the
accident happened for which we are
signing, that date is same here
in this format, date churning, so this near will be
written in this format, then when we get the house number
registered online, then
we get it at that time, then we have to
write it here, now in the next, details go,
in retail at number one is details of
insured, that is, details of those who have insurance,
we have to enter it,
first of all their name which is mentioned in the post, that is the
address of June.  That has to be
written here, house number, buildings, read name,
area, locality, what is the length
mark, near by, name of the city will be written in the city,
state, pin code will be written here and mobile
number and email ID will be mentioned here in full, on
which number details of the details of
India SEZ have been written, those who have an insurance
policy, if they have been injured or have died, then
their details will be mentioned here, but
this will also be the same for them because they have protection
from Interpol, so we will retail it, you have to
click here, there are two-three
extra things in it, first of all, this is what we will write
here, on that, designation, employee
ID and date of joining, this happens
in that case when your employer
gives you this policy, so here you have to write
not only your dedication, whatever your post is,
but after that, the employee ID which is
on your I card, at the
time of joining and date of joining, all that has to be
written in this line, next, date and
time of injury at death i.e. date and
You have to write the time, the day on which this accident happened, there was an
injury, they died,
write the date and time here, place of
injury and death, this has to be written in the next step, the
place was there and the details too, only nine accident,
how did the accident happen, where were you going, how did the accident happen, what did you
feel and how did
you react, how did you come to know about
that, now you have to write it here, the next
option is whether to report it to police, yes or
no, if you have reported to the police then you have to
write it here, otherwise you have to write them,
if you do this then
you have to write the name and address of the police station,
till you want to verify it further in the investigation, if you
want to do something from them, you can do it,
pizza bread, that individual person was
shifted to hospital immediately after the
accident, immediately after the accident, was he
immediately taken to the hospital, if yes then
tick on gas here, otherwise tick on 9
and if you do this then
we have to enter the name and address of the hospital in it, it
comes at number four, do you  On 'Have
Any Other' select Interpol C. Apart from this policy for
which you are filling the claim form,
if you have any other insurance policy, then you will have to
write the address here. At the top of the police, you get the
address of this head office at this point,
write the address there and
write the policy number. Next, so friends, you have to declare that
whatever I am writing here in the statement is
true, nothing has been
hidden in it and if the insurance company wants anything else for Gaurav Garg, if they
want to
take anything from us, they should conduct any kind of investigation, we will
operate it completely and
we give them full right to investigate in this way.
Here we will write the date, it is
not written in the date, the day on which we are filling this claim form, we will
write the place, name of our city,
signature, the injured person or the one who has been injured in the
accident will sign,
but if he is not alive, then the
nominee here will sign,
so you have to fill this form for them also,
next is long, then after fielding and
employer or  Leave the insured employer in,
both of them have to fill this form now
what is there in it is that information has been asked from their job
whether they
were on leave or at work on that day and if it is so
that they were on leave then from when to when were they on leave
and whether the winning team you have to take in the same box
now next who feels that
this Joe Roy here declared particular he came out from bidai
net for true test of
knowledge and belief all this information written on all these things
is true
nothing has been hidden in this we are filling the form through date of the
same day place where on Monday
name of city and signature of injured person
or non death happened then in which they have
said that
Chintu comes to be completed by
hospital we had asked the first question whether
he was taken to Activa hospital or
not if you say yes then you have to fill in these details
name address of hospital
name and address of hospital click here
date of admission
was admitted date of birth four days leave  The
nature of their injury has been received and how it has to be
written there, particularly for treatment,
what is their treatment, surgical operation, if
any treatment has been done, that is not written here,
all this is to be measured by the hospital's shoulder, there is nothing in it,
this hospital will
click here according to their treatment, now here in the last also there are
two hospital's science and signature, they will be
here and their name designation
who have verified this will be
written here, this hospital has to be made successful in our case,
next Dashrath three to be
completed in the event of insurance,
see if the injured person is the one in whose
name the death occurs, then
normally the details will have to be given because the
calendar is not going to be changed, then their
nominee will get a time, their name will be
here, the nominee's name will be there and
we can write the money for that, so
after nominating, the address will be there, why
fear, house number, building, street, area,
city, you can write all this, state, pin code,
after updating this, send the mobile number, email
ID, what is the
relationship of the nominee with  This is what was his relationship with him,
brother-sister, parents, his wife, then he
can write here the date on which we have to
fill this form and the place i.e. from where the
mixed form is filled and the player signature
of the injured person here will be of the nominee
and
if the injured person is Chinese then it can be his too
if he uses this phone
then here only his office will
be side idli sandwich sign-wine this is the same
that whatever information you are giving is correct,
it is not suppressed in any way or
you are not feeling under any pressure in this information
then here all the tension will be there, date,
place and signature of the injured
person or the nominee if you
want to control yourself and if the money comes in the account then you will have to
fill this form next we are talking about
light off and electronic fund
transfer i.e.
money comes in your account through electronic medium, then if you click yes here
then you will have to fill this in it, i.e. the
name of the beneficiary i.e. the name of the person whose code money will
come will appear here, their account
number type of account is savings current  Name
of Bank Name of Bank Branch Name Address
of Bank IFSC Code and MICR Code
You will find all these details on the first page of your passbook
from there you have to fold the Jadeja at
the end you have to give your Permanent Account Number i.e.
PAN number which
completes this form after this you
cannot read it by sending it all the time
significant folder I have filled the account details on these things
I will put it here then
this form gets refreshed
after doing this here now your size is
when to use this phone together see
along with this you have to attach
a and England black cancelled cheque written here on the side
these scissors teller his cancelled cheque which was
signed and a PAN card copy the
account details of drinking water a copy of his PAN card
and this is the complete
claim form filled after filling it and this copy from a card that is
why we are taking NAC there are four things there is
policy copy on number two this
platform a copy of PAN card account
details have been filled and one his cancelled cheque which has been
signed you have to cancel it by crossing
this  You have to send all four things
by courier or the day after tomorrow to
this address of the insurance company. See,
you are seeing the address to dispatch Salim
Recruitment. You have to send it from here to here.
After that, you will get a
reply here. If you want some more information, then in
this way you can fill this claim form for
personal accidental policy.
So friends, till now you have seen in the entire video
how the information of a personal accidental
policy is compiled and
what things you have to share in it. Actually, the
only purpose of filling the claim form is for the
insurance company to know in
what kind of situation the accident or any kind of claim has happened. I
hope you
liked the information. You must
write whatever questions you have in the comment section, but I also do
not know everything. It is from your questions that
I find new things and
explain those topics through messages and bring them to you. So
friends,
with the hope that you remain happy and healthy, see you
in the next video. Till then, take
care of yourself.  Be happy, thank you, pick pick pick
pick
[music]